There are 99 days left in the year. 99
days. I almost feel like this 100 day
left in the year is more important than
the New Year's resolution.
I just encourage anyone, man, this it's
the end of the year. Use this last
sprint and like treat it like an athlete
does the fourth quarter of a game and
really ask yourself like what do I want
this year to be all about? Have I have I
kind of made my mark on the year? And 99
days might sound like a short amount of
time, but that's an eternity. You can
make so much happen in 99 days. And I
just encourage anyone to just hear that
today and just ask yourself the question
like, have I made my mark on this year
yet? And if not, let's you know, there's
one sprint right here we can we can use.
>> I have two comments on that. The first
is I think the idea of quarters is so
stupid. Quarters should be months. Don't
make it Q4. Make it like M6 and then M7.
Like four weeks is a significantly
better. I've like the time that
something takes is often dictated by
like the increments that we measure them
in.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I can't stand that. Like in Google
calendars, it defaults to 30 minute
increments. I'm like, don't make it five
minute increments.
>> Uh the second I I joke with a bunch of
my Jewish friends, one of the reasons
why they're so successful is the Jewish
new year is in September. So, Rash
Rashahana, I can't even say it
correctly. Um, that was in September.
And so, I'm like, dude, you guys have
like three months head start in terms of
New Year's resolutions and like
reflecting on your year. And so, I was
thinking about that where like I I've
actually like that where you make New
Year's resolutions like two months in
advance. And so, you got a two-month
head start on everyone.
>> Well, there's a I think it's called
Parkinson's law, which is like work
expands to fill the time you give it.
It's like um it's like modeled after
physics like a a gas will expand to fill
whatever container it's in. So if you
shrink the container, the gas will be
more compact. If you have a bigger
container, it'll spread out. Your
projects take the work the same way. And
so if you default to like you said
Google calendar, if the default meeting
is 30 minutes or an hour, guess what?
You'll find a way to talk for 30
minutes. If you had moved that same
meeting to 22 minutes, you would have
got it all done in 22 minutes. So yeah,
I think take this 99 days and make it
happen. I I What where are you at with
that? Do you do you think this way? Do
you I know you're trying not to be the
kind of ADD entrepreneur or the cortisol
entrepreneur anymore that's like spiking
in in stress.
>> Yeah, I'm trying to fight my natural
instincts.
>> Um how's that going?
>> So it's
it's good. I think my theory is that you
can't change your weaknesses or it's
really hard to make your weaknesses a
strength. you can potentially neutralize
it, but that's like the best case
scenario. And so instead, you do
something where you just create a system
where your weakness like can't really
show itself. So like, for example, if
you don't work out, you're like, "Well,
I'm never going to be selfotivated, but
if I prepay for this trainer to show up
at my home, like I'm still going to be
lazy, but like they're going to I just
have to do this. Like there's no
choice." So with me, I've got a CEO, my
co-founder Joe, and so we have set it up
to where we only talk mostly about
personal stuff throughout the day, but
there's only one day of the week where I
can come and complain to him or suggest
improvements for the business. And that
one day a week, it's only 45 minutes.
And I have to write it out in advance.
And so because of that, I'll like see
something and get pissed off and I'll be
like 6 days later when we talk about it,
I'm like, I'm not actually that angry.
Right? And so like I'm a big fan of
creating systems. So it's worked for me.
Uh do you have anything um major that
you want to do over the next 90?
>> Um yeah, I want there's like one more
event I want to create. I've realized
that
as the world is so online, so digital, I
think it's just put premiums on
everything that's IRL. So I want to
create one more IRL event. We have Hoop
Group, which is our basketball event
that we do once a year. And I want to
create a second. And that thing's been
like such a blessing, right? It's like
super fun, super fun to do. Unbelievable
crew of people that come to that thing
and it's built this awesome network
around something that I would just do
for fun anyways. And uh I want to do
another one of those. The problem with
that one is it's so exclusive. Like not
only is everybody there like
kind of like the top of the top like you
know uh in terms of the their careers,
but also you have to be like really into
basketball which is fundamentally
limiting for a lot of people. They're
just not that into basketball. So I want
to create another event that is not
limited in that same way.
>> Launch it or host it.
>> Yeah. It's going to happen before the
end of the year.
>> Okay.
>> And I don't even have the concept yet.
So that's okay. Um but you know how long
does an idea take? Like that's how long
an idea takes, right? How long does the
decision take? A decision takes that
long too. So you know I kind of people
would would normally say oh that's not
enough time. If you ask any professional
event planner they'd say that's not
enough time. Thankfully I'm not a
professional event planner and I will
make it happen in that amount of time.
>> I think the best way to become
successful is to see how other people
did it. Whether you're going to copy
them or just use it as inspiration
because then now you know what's
possible. So starting at the age of 24,
I did this relentlessly and I was very
methodical about it and I created a
spreadsheet where I tracked roughly 50
people who were uber successful and I
looked at the year that they were born,
the year that they started their
apprenticeship and then the year that
they started, the first thing that made
them successful, finally the year that
they broke through. And I aggregated all
this data along with the stories of what
they did to be an apprentice and what
they did to finally break through. and I
put it together in a database and
HubSpot went and found this thing that I
frankly even forgot about, but it did
change my life and they resurfaced it.
They made it even better and they put it
into a thing that you can download for
free right now. So, if you click the
link in the description or click the QR
code right here, you can see this
database that I made when I was 24 and
it changed my life. And so, if you're
looking to become successful or you're
already successful and just want some
more inspiration, check it out. So, uh,
for the listener, my last company was it
was the hustle was a newsletter, but it
started as an event. And it was
basically one event that I would host
like basically when I needed money. So,
like every nine months
like I would do it, use the money and go
hang out for like two months and then
like do it again. I did that for like
three events in a row and then it became
a newsletter. But the first event that I
hosted, I'm going to try and get the
dates correctly. The event happened I
think on July 1st. I started working on
it on May 15th, so it was roughly six
weeks and so I sort of had first mover
advantage and so I could kind of be
crappy and it still be kind of
interesting. And uh I think I charged
$300 and I think roughly 350 people
came. I I'll frame it differently. I
think what you did brilliantly was the
name of it was HustleCon and the vibe of
it was scrappy entrepreneurs, the real
deal. And the beauty of that was you
didn't have to provide a polished
luxurious thing because that was
off-brand.
So, thank God I don't have any of that
because that would be off brand anyways.
It's like uh I have a friend who who
created Summit series, the big like
event they do on like the mountain. They
bought they ended up the the event that
where they ended up buying the mountain
where they
>> they bought a Summit. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And he said the best thing Burning
Man ever did was create the ethos of
like, hey, like it's a piece of dirt.
You create the town, you clean up the
town. It's like where there's no there's
no there's no sign.
If we didn't have the right sign where
the bathroom was, people would get
upset.
>> Burning Man, they just changed the
expectation where it's like, "Of course,
we're not going to baby you.
>> You You set up your own tent. You
survive. You bring your own supplies.
You clean up everything." And they he's
like, he's like, "From an event planning
perspective." Brilliant.
>> Yeah. Um it's great. Um and so I'll be
eager to see how you pull this off. It's
definitely pull off aable. It's just
like a lot of pressure. It is a very
stressful period and it's sort of like
running a marathon where leading up to
it you're like this is kind of cool. It
gets closer and you're like I'm scared.
This sucks. Never doing this again. The
day happens. You don't really remember a
lot of it. It was a lot of work. A week
later you're like
>> I can do this again and I can make it
better. You know, it's like giving birth
and hosting and hosting an event and
running a marathon or all
>> hosting an allmale tech conference.
>> Those are the two similar similar
events. Yeah. I also think you know
constraints are very very important. So
time constraint is one constraint. You
said money you know we do the events out
of pocket. We don't make any money off
of them intentionally. So well that's a
little bit silly. Why why do you do
that? Well, because the constraint is
what is an event that is so good that is
so so fun, so valuable, so meaningful to
us that we'd be willing to spend, you
know, 150 to 250 grand to make it
happen. And that literally just
eliminates like 99 options of what you
might do if the goal was to try to make
100 grand or try to make 200 grand, make
300 grand, make a million dollars. Um,
and so the conra so using the constraint
of what's an event so good I would paid
I would pay to host it is what's led us
to creating you know some very unique
events so far and that's that's kind of
what I want to do again I want to give
you a little anecdote that I thought was
pretty interesting so there's this guy
Joel Greenblat do you know who that is
um he writes books on stock picking
right
>> yeah he's like one of the one of the
best uh investors uh you know of all
time so like like Warren Buffett he
outperformed the market for decades
using a strategy, but but you know,
nonetheless outperformed and did really
well. So, he goes to give a talk and he
puts in the front in this like in the
front of of the auditorium, he's got
this jar of jelly beans inside. And so,
he says, "Hey, I'm going to Anybody can
come on up. Come on up to the front,
take a look at the jar, and I want you
to write down an estimate. Don't show
your friend. Don't don't show your
neighbor. Write down an estimate for how
many jar how many beans are in this jar
on this piece of paper." And he's like,
"You could, you know, you can't open it,
but you can do whatever you want. Come
up here and take a look." So, everyone
goes, they take a look. Some people are
counting the the beans in the row and
then the height and kind of try to
estimate it. And so, um, he tallies up.
He gets all the the results. And, um,
the guesses are 1,771
beans.
>> That's the average of the guesses.
>> That's the average of all the guesses.
Now, guess what? That's only five off
from the actual. There's 1,776
beans in there. the average of this
group of a 100 people was incredibly
close. Um, but he doesn't tell them how
close they were. Then he goes around the
room and he says, "Actually, you know
what? Let's make this a little little
faster. Um, why don't you just tell me
how many you think are in this thing?
Say it out loud." So the first person
says, "Uh, 850."
And so the next person who might have
been thinking 2,000 was like, "Oh [ __ ]
2,000 maybe that's way off. Um, 1300."
And then the person who was thinking
1,700 like 850 and 1300 and they so they
they all say their guesses out loud.
When they all said their guesses out
loud, they went from being off by five
to being 50% off. The guess the average
I think came down to like 900 or
something like that. So they were off by
a mile now. Same people, same jar. The
only thing that changed was hearing what
other people thought. And he gave this
example. He goes, "This is the stock
market." For most of you, if you if you
were able to independently think and
analyze a business and try to come up
with what you think the true value of
that business is, you're smart people,
you do pretty well. But the reason smart
people don't do well in the stock market
is cuz they're listening to the news and
Jim Kramer and the analyst reports and
then they look at the ticker and it's
going down. I guess it's bad. And it's
going up. Ah, I got to get in and so
it's got to go higher, right? and and
they let everybody else influence their
thinking as to what the business is
actually worth and goes if I to if you
remember one thing about how to be a
great investor, it would be to look at
the jar and write down the piece the
number on the piece of paper and know
that on average you will be much closer
to the true value than if you just
listen to what everybody is saying. And
he goes, now this is so difficult.
There's a reason Warren Buffett says you
should buy lowcost index funds even
though he doesn't. And I say you should
buy lowcost index funds even though I
don't because it is so hard to do what I
just told you.
>> So we had Joe Hudson on the other day.
>> So I consider myself to be a fairly
easily influenced person. Like I'll hear
about Sam New House and I'm like that's
awesome. I love that. I'm easily
excitable maybe is is a good word. And
so he said something that was
interesting um where he was like um I
forget exactly how he's phrased it but
whatever the way he phrased it I went
and started reading this book called
untethered soul which is kind of a fine
book it's only fine but there was like
one concept that I found was interesting
so have you heard of transcendental
meditation you basically uh sit down and
instead of being quiet with your
thoughts you're chanting and you're
chanting something it doesn't even
matter what you're saying but it's the
rhythmic auditory thing almost drowns
out the the thoughts in your head. I've
done this before. There's a Buddhist
practice that's like this that I was
once taken to I thought it was really
pretty awesome. Uh but I don't do it
regularly.
>> Yeah. And and I've done it as well and I
don't do it regularly anymore. Uh but
like there was one line from unt
untethered soul where he talks about the
guy who created TM transcendental
meditation. His name was his last name
was Yogi. Uh uh but he like tells the
story where he's like basically like the
most important key to have like a happy
life is when you have these thoughts in
your brain, you you should treat that
that thing in your brain as a roommate.
And so if you were to have a roommate
that said, "You totally screwed that up.
You suck. Like that was not good what
you did. You are never going to make up
for like everyone has these like
negative thinking. You have to be like
dude you are not me. You are my
roommate." And with this guy who created
TM, he was like, you just have to ask
yourself all the time. For every
thought, you have to ask, why am I
thinking this? And like I'll just I'll
I'll hear it, but I'm not going to
listen to it. But I have to ask myself
on a consistent basis, who am I? And why
am I thinking about this? And what does
this mean for me? As opposed to just
listening. And just the act of asking
yourself that is actually really
important. And that simple question
oftentimes can have breakthroughs for
self-enlightenment. And so because I'm a
very influenced person, I have to like
read something and be like, why does
this excite me? Okay, but is this the is
this actually who I am? And like this
constant like who am I? Is this who I
am? It's okay to like this person's
story. That doesn't mean I'm going to
copy it. Um like this this like constant
inner dialogue because I've been asking
myself, how do you become less
influenced by people who aren't aligned
with what you your life's calling or
like your mission is? And so when it
comes to like this mimedic
discussion of like how do you not let
this person influence you, I'm just
trying to look for exercises on how to
actually combat that because it is
incredibly hard.
>> Yeah. Although you're talking about the
and you're saying you're taking it to
the extreme. You're like even the voice
in my head. Don't let that don't let
that necessarily influence me cuz that
thing is a you know monkey throwing
feces all over the room. You know, it's
like it's not necessarily the most
reliable aligned source for me.
>> Like it is not you. It is just a
roommate.
>> I love the roommate thing. I love the
roommate thing. That's great. Have I
told you about my five five voices in
the head theory?
>> No. Is one of them telling you to kill
cuz we should talk about that.
>> So, I I believe that people It's not one
roommate. I think there's this five
voices in the head. And once you know
that that these uh these parts of you
exist, you'll start to recognize them
because they'll pop up. It's kind of
like the movie Inside Out. if you've
ever seen it. And inside the girl's
head, there's like she they do it with
emotions. There's like the red angry
guy, there's the blue sad girl, there's
the fearful one, and then there's the
grossed out one. So the Inside Out
showed this in a movie with emotions,
but I think there's a similar thing
going on with voices in your head. Who
are the five? The first one is the
critic. And the critic is like David
Gogggins in your head. You're never
enough for him. You did you did 100
push-ups. You should have done 200. You
could have done more, you [ __ ] And
he's there for a reason. He serves you,
keeps you honest, prevents you from
getting high on your own supply. There's
a reason that he gets to have a room.
But god darn it, if you listen to that
guy too often, you know, life life
doesn't end up very well for you. Then
you have uh another voice, and I call
this the voice of the mother. And the
voice of the mother is a more caring
voice, but it's also the one that's
protective. It's trying to, you know,
it's slicing your grapes for you even
when you're 19 years old. It doesn't
want you to get hurt. and wants you to
live a nice safe life and be protected
and wants everything to go well for you.
And that's great, too, because it's nice
to be protected. It's nice to to be to
play it safe and you don't want to take
too much risk, but at the same time, the
dose makes the poison. Too much of that
can also ruin your life because you'll
play it too safe. And you go on and you
go you go forth. And so there's these
different voices. I could go through all
of them, but like that that's the idea
is that there's these five different
voices. And then at the end of it, if
you're able to hush up all these voices
and get them to go back to their room
for a little bit, the thing that's left,
that's you. The last voice is you.
That's the self. And the problem is
we're so it's so noisy in there because
these other voices are constantly
chirping that it's hard to hear what you
truly what you truly think, what you
truly want because it sounds so easy.
Well, you should just do what you want.
Most people don't even know. So, why do
we do things like meditation? Why does
sleep help? Why do we do therapy?
Because you're trying to get these other
voices to just shut the up for a minute.
So, you can actually just figure out
what you want and then go do that. It's
pretty easy once you get there.
>> Have you ever described anything to uh
AI and you like describe this like
really like interesting thought? You're
like, I think I just came up with this
cool idea. And they're like, yeah, dude,
that's called the theory of relativity.
And you're like, so I'm as smart as
Albert. We both we invented this
concurrently. Um
>> well, is it is this a thing? Is this a
thing that exists?
>> Yeah. Well, there's this great book
called The Six Thinking Hats. I found
this to be a very productive book.
>> Edward Deono.
>> Uh I believe is that I'm looking it up.
Who? I think that might be him. Uh yeah.
Yeah, you're right.
>> The lateral thinking guy. Yeah. And it's
like basically like often times at work
or like um when you're working on a
project like typically there's always
the guy who like defaults to like that
can't work because right and I remember
reading that and I'm like how or
thinking about that I'm like how do I
change this guy or change myself and so
there's the six hats of thinking and one
of them's like the guy the white hat is
focus on facts the yellow hat is be
optimistic the black hat be devil's
advocate whatever and there's like six
hats and like when you're having a
discussion you're like okay I hear what
you're saying can you go ahead and like
tell me like if you were an optimist
what would you say about this idea and
like you it just it creates a
significantly better conversation where
you're like okay listen to this voice I
hear you are you you're being this
person that might be who you are I need
you to pretend that you're uh an
optimist person and like tell me like
>> uh or like okay you're this creative
like we used to have creative people at
uh at the hustle and it's like okay
you're saying this crazy idea I need you
to be a manager
right now think through a manager's
perspective and tell me how this makes
profit so I can continue paying
everyone's salary and it's like okay
let's think through that lens and it
starts like actually changing the
conversation meaningfully so what you've
described is a little bit similar to
what one of my favorite business authors
of all time has described so
congratulations you are now
>> my favorite business author
yeah all right sweet that's a win for me
by the way I like doing this the the
physical version of this so I actually
have like two two hats that I use. So
when I was I told you I was studying the
creative
>> Did you literally put your hat on?
>> Yeah. So I I I was studying the creative
process and and one of the biggest
things in the creative process is that
you need what Jerry Seinfeld calls two
minds. The two minds of a creator and
the first mind is this uh childlike
mind. So you know when you want to sit
down and create, you're sitting in front
of a blank page. The reason people have
writer's block, the reason people
struggle to to to create daily is
because you're afraid. You're afraid of
failure. You're afraid of looking bad.
you're afraid of. You want so badly to
be great that you're not willing to do
something bad, to not put something bad
down on the page. So, you put nothing
down at all as a self-protective
mechanism. So, he talks about how you
need the childlike mine at the beginning
who's just going to grab a crayon and
just scribble and and then you and you
almost want to have this attitude
towards that that version of you that's
like, "Oh my god, sweetie, that's
amazing. Can I hang that up on the
fridge?" And like you need to nurture
that like that energy because it's
what's going to get you going, right?
It's going to get you to put things on
the page and then you you'll eventually
figure out how to make it good. Good
comes later. Don't worry about that.
>> So, you need this childlike mine. He's
like, and then what happens is about 4
hours later when you come back and you
you now have a bunch of scribble on the
page, you have to completely change into
a ruthless [ __ ] And you now this is
the editor and the editor is basically
saying, "No, no, no, less of this. Trim
the fat. Too many words. Too many
syllables. Cut down. Rearrange this."
And you you got to be able to do both.
you know, somebody who can only do the
free play and never edits, never has any
kind of like discernment or taste or
judgment, um, doesn't work. But if you
bring the judgment into the room early
on in the brainstorm, you're not going
to have a very good brainstorm. And so
we created these two hats literally like
Diego got them made for us, which was
like, uh, it says Rick mode, which is
like Rick Rubin. So it's like Rick mode
when it's like, dude, we're just messing
around. We're playing, we're just we
trust ourselves. And you're Rick mode.
And then we have prick mode. and you put
on the prick mode hat, it goes the other
way. It's a different color. And if you
were if we were in prick mode, then it's
like, well, that's who I'm supposed to
be right now, so let me go ahead and do
that. And I I at first I felt kind of
silly and then I started noticing
there's a lot of examples of great
people who do this. So Warren Buffett
has a a actual thing on his desk called
the two hard pile cuz his investing
philosophy is that look, you can't have
a great opinion on a hundred straight
stocks or investment opportunities. is
like you should be able to pretty
quickly figure out the five that are
very interesting probably like you know
good good no-brainer things to do the
five that are absolutely terrible duds
stay away red red red flags everywhere
but then 90% it's too hard to judge it's
too close to call can't tell and so he
literally creates the two hard pile on
his desk so that he can put things in
there just mentally say look I I don't
have to come to an answer it's just in
the too hard pile I don't need to worry
about it
>> um there was a guy Zack Dell so the son
of Michael Dell from Dell Computers and
Zack Dell's got this really interesting
company called Base Power now and he was
on a podcast and he was saying he's like
I have two notebooks. So he's like so I
got the I forgot what it was like the
red notebook and the blue notebook and I
think you will like this because this is
every business like CEO business owner
has this. He goes the red notebook is
working in the business. So if I have an
idea of what we should, you know, what
we should do, what we should change
this, you know, this customer thing, and
then the blue is working on the
business, which is, oh, you know, this
person's not in the right role or we
need to hire somebody for this or, you
know, we need to we need to get an
office. We need to rearrange our office
space so these two groups are sitting
closer to each other so that they're
going to have better chemistry. And so
in the business and on the business and
he's like, I have two separate notebooks
so I know which one I'm doing when and I
know if I'm spending too much time in
the business, it's like I'm all over the
red notebook. Is that Is that it? Do you
have the same thing?
>> Two notebooks, baby.
>> Can we just admire the showmanship? Can
I just do that again? Instant replay.
Sam picks up the notebook, shows it like
that where it looks like one thick
notebook, turns, fans it out. Two
notebooks.
>> Yeah, I have got two notebooks. Um, I
actually have a third. Hang on.
>> But wait, there's more. The ultimate
showman. Hey, Zach. Suck on this.
>> In the business, on the business, and
out of business.
>> Well, one is like this is like um
>> uh it's like the five day fiveear
journal that I write where it's like
here's how I feel today, like right now.
The next one is like content ideas, like
just random ideas. And then the next one
is like here's what I actually have to
do and like I need to like work through
the actual problem.
>> What's your system for this?
Um, so this one I I do almost
religiously every day. So this is the
five-year journal. So every day I write
like here's what I here's what I did
today. Here's something to be grateful
for.
>> So this is like 5 10 minutes in the
morning. What do you do?
>> No, 3 minutes. So it could be like uh
>> uh today I I read about Aristotle and I
loved it for these reasons and I need to
be reminded to do X like Aristotle. Or
it could be like today I went to San
Francisco. It was amazing. um we brought
um help with us and it made the trip so
much easier. So it could be like just
like just it just like I'll look back at
a year like ah that's a good reminder.
Uh the next one this one uh will be more
like uh like you know like um let's say
I'm reading a book and I'll like have
like an interesting idea related to that
book. So I just need to get on paper.
And then the next one is like here's
what I have to do today. Uh, and like
it's mostly checklists, but I'll like
kind of brainstorm solutions to the
problem.
>> So,
your boys got books. Um,
and by the way, that's like a a
consistent thing I've noticed amongst
creators that I like is that they I
think the easiest way to say it is they
write drunk, edit sober.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, so I've noticed that consistently,
but then you have stories like Eminem,
his the famous story where he walked in
with Dr. Dre and like Dre plays the
first beat and then within 5 seconds he
goes hi my name is like you're like okay
so like it definitely could just happen
but typically the people who are
systematically great including Eminem
like people I've seen um I think
Anderson Cooper did a thing a story on
Eminem where they're like dude he writes
like crazy like I've never seen someone
write down so much stuff and another
thing that they would say about him and
Eminem when he was younger came off as
this like party guy maybe he was but
they're like he's at the studio at 9:00
a.m. and he goes home at 4. Like it's
it's a work day. And like I notice that
there's way more systematic ways to
being creative than there is examples of
epiphies,
>> right? Well, the the analogy I would use
cuz I think it's yeah, both. Like I
think yeah, you have those moments where
um the song comes on, the beat comes on
and he starts doing Hi, My name is or
that you hear this a lot where somebody
it's like in 24 hours they wrote both of
the hit songs that define their careers
in one day. all it took was one day and
it's like no all it took was every day
for their whole life and then they had
that day and and the analogy I use is
you know
>> you have a 2% conversion rate and the
conversions just came like in number 98
and
>> 99 yeah well the the analogy I use is
imagine your brain as this like old
mansion old mansion on a hill and you go
to you inherited it you find out you
inherited this gift from your you know
your great-grandfather you didn't even
know you had it but it was yours and so
you go you walk in like wow this thing's
amazing it's in terrible shape cobweb is
everywhere, but this thing's going to be
amazing. And you decide, you go to the
restroom, you go to the bathroom, and
you see this like wonderful this old
tub, this amazing tub, and you're like,
"Man, this is this is crazy. I've never
had a bath like this. I I'm going to
turn it on." You turn the water on, and
of course, right when you turn the water
on, it's creaky. Takes a second. It
sputters, and then out comes brown,
muddy water, like the most disgust. And
you're you flinch. You're like
horrified. You're like, "Oh,
disgusting." You turn it off. This is
this is the you know the first thing you
write when you sit down to write. The
first thing you you say if I said hey
freestyle right now it's what would come
out. You'd be horrified at your own
disgust. It's your own like your own
output is going to be it's going to
disgust you. But you you know what do
you do? So most people just turn the
water off and say oo never again. That
bathtub has it's nasty. Don't go in
there. Um but a few people are like they
leave the water running. And sure enough
it's brown. It's brown. It's brown. It's
brown. It's brown. And then eventually
it starts little spurts of clear come
out and eventually the water starts
running clear. And I think what happens
in that example where Eminem goes in and
freestyles is that he's had the water
running and he's running clear.
>> And so you know when the when the moment
comes,
he's able to perform. He's able to come
up with an idea. He's able to have a
good idea because that it's warmed up.
The whole system is warmed up. The muddy
water is gone because he's got putting
in the daily reps, you know, along the
way. And so I think that's a lot of how
this works. And uh you know I feel that
way about this podcast. Like let's say
we didn't do this podcast for three
months.
One might think that oh we're going to
be we're going to have so much saved up
material. We're going to be awesome.
It's going to be so much better.
>> And then as you know
>> it would be way worse. It would be
terrible. This podcast gets better the
more often we do it. Obviously there's
some limits to that. Like if I did it
again in two hours, like maybe I'd be
out of I need a little fresh feed
stocks, a little inspiration, a little
fresh air in between.
>> You got to get warmed up.
>> But by and large, the more you keep the
water running, the better your the you
know, the clearer it eventually starts
to run. And it's when you stop using it
for a while that you know, it's like
there's this flywheel where the more it
generates, the better it generates. And
the less it generates, the worse it
generates.
>> There's a story about Tupac Shakur who
uh died when he was only 25. And so he
was very prolific for a very short
amount of time. And there's a story he
goes to he went to prison for uh doing
some bad stuff and he's there for like 9
months and someone was like well it must
have been like you know let's find the
icing of the cake like at least you had
like a lot of solitude so you could like
write he goes I can't write in here it's
the worst like a there's like very
little inspiration and b like I can't
get it out. He would write way better
when he was like a machine gun in the
studio like just go go go. All right we
did that one. All right let's try
another one. Can I tell you an
interesting story? And this is sort of
related to like someone who followed
none of the rules that people default
to. And I think it's really interesting
and I think it's going to interest you
because A, it's an obscure billionaire
who I'm sure you've never heard of, but
you know their work and B, it's a family
dynasty business which I think you're
tiptoeing into like your interests.
>> I'm tantalized.
>> Okay. Have you ever heard of Advanced
Publishing?
>> No. But you said I know their product.
What's the product? Well, the most
popular ones, but not necessarily the
most profitable are Iron Man, GQ
Magazine, Reddit, Charter
Communications, Warner Bros., Discovery.
Some smaller ones that you probably like
is the or you've heard of American City
Business Journals, Turnitin.com.
They just bought a mountain biking
event, Vanity Fair, GQ, Vogue,
>> Reddit. Reddit's Reddit's a public
stock. What do you What do you mean they
own Reddit?
>> They owned Reddit before it was public.
So, I can I'll tell you. and and they
still own I think they own 30% of it
still. But I'll tell you the story. So
there's this guy named Sam New House.
Sam New House was born I think in like
1895. He's born into this like Jewish
family. He's like 5'2. He's like a
little guy. He's tiny. And he his father
gets sick, gets really bad asthma. And
so his he can't work. And so he's got
like four other siblings. And he's like
at the age of 13 and 14, the mom is
like, "Hey dude, you're the man of the
house. You got to you got to drop out of
school and help me pay the bills." And
so he does like a mail-in order course,
basically the equivalent of an online
course in bookkeeping. And he convinces
this local uh business person to give
him a job. He's like, "I'll do your
bookkeeping." So he does his bookkeeping
starting at the age of 15. By 16, a year
later, the business guy who owns a very
small local newspaper, and he's like,
"Hey, I have this newspaper that I own.
It doesn't really make a lot of money,
and it made like the equivalent of like
$800,000 a year in revenue today." He's
like, "Can you just like keep an eye on
this? you seem very trustworthy, you
know numbers. Figure out how to make
this work. Within six or seven months,
he turns it around and start making
money. And he's at this point 17. And
the guy's like, "Dude, good job. Here,
I'll give you uh a percentage of the
profits now and I'll also give you a
little bit of ownership." And Sam New
House is like, "I like this. I think I'm
pretty good at it." So, he does it for a
couple more years and then after about 3
years, he convinces um a bunch of family
members to all pitch in and loan him
money and he buys his first newspaper.
It was called Satin Island Advance,
which is why the company today is still
called Advance Publishing. And so his
whole shtick is basically he bought this
newspaper and he goes into it with a few
things in mind. The first thing he's
like, "Look, we're just here to sell
ads. Let's let's keep it real. The the
the content that we create, we can make
it as good as we possibly can within our
constraints, but like we need to make a
profit." And so he's very very very good
at selling ads and he's very good at
keeping cost controls down. And for the
next I think 60 years he buys a new
newspaper every three years and it
slowly accumulates roughly 15 to 20% per
year in revenue growth and he grows and
he grows and he grows and he grows and
by the time it's like 1980 he has one of
the largest privatelyowned
companies in America and he's doing like
well today Advanced Publishing does like
8 billion a year in revenue. Back then
it was doing like a billion in revenue.
But what's interesting is this little
guy named Sam New House, he never had an
office. He worked out of a briefcase.
All he had was a briefcase. Most of the
deals that he did was handshake
agreements. He had zero partners. He had
zero executive management team. And by
the time the company was doing a billion
in revenue, it was literally just him,
like just him making these decisions.
And and he would in he would hire a
publisher of which is basically a GM or
like a CEO of a newspaper. And he would
go to each one each week and be like,
"Hey, what's going on, man? How's
everything going?" He was very polite
though.
>> He was the headquarters just driving
around.
>> He and he would drive from thing to
thing to thing. And he kept doing this
and doing this and doing this. And then
after a while, when he's like close to
60 and 70 and 80 years old, he starts
getting his sons involved. And they've
now created this like dynasty. And it
was his sons who was like, "Okay, our
dad bought all these like kind of low
prestige local newspapers where like
they pretty much just exist to buy ads."
Basically, the way that he thought about
it, he was like, his whole thing was
like, "How much profit can I make in 10
years off of this particular newspaper?"
That's how he would value things. So, he
was like, "Okay, I can make $8 million
in profit over the next 10 years off
this newspaper. I have no problem buying
it for $4 million." which is like I
think at the time that like he would buy
them for six to eight times uh annual
earnings cuz he was like I'm looking for
10 years at a time. That's how I measure
it. And he kept going and then
eventually his kids were like okay dad
built like a cool company but like it's
not like well regarded. We want to do
something great. And so they buy the New
Yorker which was at the time very
prominent magazine. They buy this little
thing called Kai Nast. And Kanye Nass
was a series of uh magazines including
Vanity Fair, Vogue, and all this other
stuff uh like GQ. And they were like,
we're going to make this like we're
going to make our family great. And so
they come up with this idea of Vanity
Fair, which is hard to describe now
because it's not as relevant, but they
were like, we're going to hire these
amazing uh editors. And that's where
they get this woman named Anna Winter,
who if you've seen like The Devil Wears
Prada, that's her. And their whole
shtick was we're going to give the hire
these amazing editors and we're going to
give them like do whatever you want as
long as it like makes some profit. Do
whatever you want. We don't care. And
that's what they were famous for. And so
they've had a bunch of editors of these
really awesome magazines for like three
or four decades. I think she's been
doing it for like 30 years. And then
come the dot era, they were like, "Okay,
we've got to figure this out. What do we
do?" And so they buy Reddit for $10
million and they hold on to it and it
grows and it grows and it grows and
eventually they spit it out and do its
own thing and so their $10 million
investment into Reddit is worth I think
now like between $2 and3 billion.
>> Yeah, that's wild.
>> They've like done this over and over and
over again. They're still a privately
held company. I believe his name is
Steven New House who must be the great
the grandson of the founder. He recently
bought Iron Man, the triathlon series.
They've bought uh they just bought a
mountain biking uh event. They um own
Turnitin.com, but I think they recently
bought that for over a billion dollars.
Uh they own 4% of Warner Brothers, which
owns HBO, CNN, Discovery Channel, all
this other stuff. Uh they own 14% of
Charter Communications. And so it's just
this big like playground where they like
buy these really cool things and they
own them forever.
>> This is fascinating. what what's
something you're going to, you know,
you're like, I can steal from this
playbook.
>> So, something that he did that I believe
Warren Buffett did, um, when you're
buying multiple businesses, something
that you tell yourself that's cool is to
consolidate the back end, the back
office. It's counterintuitive. That is
not the way to do it. Every entity
should be its own thing that's uh can
run itself and is completely
independent. that is the best way to
make sure that they can move fast and
act on what's good for their local
business as opposed to having like some
HR or sorry some HQ that's helping make
decisions. Another thing is I need to be
reminded of this all the time. I think
everyone does is how if you know what
business you're in, even if it's not
sexy and you're able to stick with it
for a long time and you are what you are
and you know what you are, it can really
work a lot better than pretending to be
something else. for example, he knew he
was like, "Guys, ads are first." Okay?
So, if we hire journalists, that's fine.
Uh that are great journalists, but you
have to like stick within this playbook.
We aren't going to like appeal to like
be sexy. It was his kids who got into
that cuz they wanted to be that, but he
was like, "No, this is what we're doing.
This is the mission, and we're going to
do it over and over and over and over
again." Like you and I will like talk
about this podcast often times, and
we're like, this is a fake example, but
we're like, "Should we talk about
politics?" And like one could say like
yeah we should it'll get more popular.
We'll get it's like or we just stick to
what we know and like enjoy our niche
and just be kings of that small niche.
Do you know what I mean?
>> Yeah. So that's a big takeway.
>> Very tempting to um I wouldn't even say
tempting. I think it is interesting when
people don't really understand the
business that they're in. And um that
can be from a a customer point of view
like why like you know for example why
do people listen to this podcast just to
just to use a personal example right
it's like if you can't really understand
why somebody's listening what are the
odds you're going to be fulfilling that
you know at the highest level that
you're going to be delivering to the
person the reason they came the job to
be done for why they're here right
because on one level you could say for
this podcast well they're listening for
business ideas because you would say
well often we talk about different
business ideas or opportunities and
certainly it's for somebody who's
looking for their next business. So then
we should go market this as a great
podcast for somebody who's looking for
their next business. And if you did
that, it would be a shockingly small
number of people and a small percentage
of our actual audience because what our
actual audience likes to do is be
entertained by the talk of business,
right? Like I like to hear about
business ideas that I have no plan on
ever going and doing. It sounds
irrational. Why would you do that? Why
waste the mind space there? And it's
like, well, because it tickles some part
of my brain to hear people brainstorming
about an idea or teaching me about an
idea that I never am going to do. And or
I hear about a business that's
completely different than mine, but I'm
fascinated by it. I take inspiration
from it. And I for some reason hearing
about this dude's old newspaper business
and how he was a traveling you know
traveling in his car checking on each
each HQ and how he took a simple idea
seriously and he stuck with it for you
know hundred years it made me reinforce
what I'm doing over here in the
restaurant business what I'm doing over
here in the oil business or whatever
other business you're in. And so we have
to understand that for us it's inspiring
stories. So stories of people doing
badass things to make it so that you go
do badass things in your business. And
secondly, people who are just business
junkies, they just like to know. They
like to hear. They like to the fantasy
football of the whole thing. They don't
have to go plan to actually go do that
thing. And once you understand that, you
might like run your product or run your
business a little bit differently.
>> Yeah. Like a good example of what not to
do is do you remember Jaguar had like a
rebrand like two years ago?
>> Oh yeah. Everyone hated it, right? What
were they doing?
>> Yeah. So basically like Jaguar they're
historically I think they were like it's
a British company and it was like a cool
guy car like uh James Bond would drive a
jet. Yeah. It was like a cool guy like a
like a man's man kind of thing. And I
think they drifted a little bit away
from that but that's like the heart of
it. And so they they they were trying to
figure out they're like look we kind of
been like this middleman car company for
the last 15 20 years. We got to get back
to our roots. And they go and do this
rebrand. And somehow when they did it,
they had like their spokesperson was
like an androgynous woman, which isn't
exactly in line with a some a manly man
who loves to smell gasoline. It sort of
seemed like like a little like it was
like related to the LGBTQ thing, which
is like fine, but that's not exactly the
Jaguar customer or like the reason why
people turn to Jaguar. And when they did
that, all the customers were like, "What
is this? This doesn't speak to us." And
so it was like the exact opposite of
what you should do.
>> Well, right now Nike is in the news for
the same thing. Nike stock is down 90
what is it down 80% 90% something like
that from its peak. Um I don't know if
you've been following this, but
>> yeah. What's the What's the gist of it?
I know it's down.
>> Peak was 170 and it's currently at 36.
So Nike stock has fallen dramatically.
It's now a $53 billion market cap.
>> And just to put that in perspective,
they do 46 billion in revenue. So
they're trading almost at one times
their revenue
>> like a shitty DDC brand, right? Yeah.
>> And there's lots of reasons people can
attribute to this. One of the popular
reasons, I don't know if this is the
full reason, right? I think there was
some business model things they did, but
one of the popular kind of complaints or
cons things that people say is like look
Nike the brand the premium you were
getting was because you had this
incredible brand and it was worldwide
recognized and respected brand and
athletes everywhere wanted to be a part
of and it used to Nike used to celebrate
greatness you know famously they would
never show the shoe they would talk
about the athlete and the athlete being
great the athlete pushing through the
athlete achieving what others said was
impossible and they just so happened to
be be wearing Nikes. And the implication
is if you want to be great, Nike stood
for greatness, stood for for excellence.
And if you wanted to be great, if you
wanted to be truly excellent, then you
should wear Nike. And it drifted. And so
like they started having like all these
like body positives. So it's like, all
right, there's a fat person wearing
Nike. Great. Like, you know, there's a
you know, there's a this person who's
not not great wearing wearing Nike, not
great at their sport. And it's like,
well, nobody wants to bribe the brand of
of non-exellent athletic performance for
an athletic shoe. And uh you could see
how a large corporation could drift and
could lose lose that. Then they're going
to have now they're going to have their
back to their roots moment where they're
going to trim the product lines and
they're going to go back to their roots.
They're going to overpay some athlete to
to go back and they're going to have
this new campaign. They're going to fire
their ad agency and hire a new ad
agency. They're going to get back to
their roots.
Think of all the athletes. They're like,
"I could be Nike's next mistake. Let's
like I have to get in. I have to get in
before they realize how dumb this is."
>> And so, yeah, like I shouldn't have a
chance
at being on the Nike billboard, right?
Like, that should be impossible.
>> Can I wrap up here with a um a segment
that I want to call I created a monster
slash how to turn [ __ ] into gold?
This is brought to you by Jiffy Lube.
>> Yeah, I feel like every segment needs a
sponsor, even a fictitious one.
>> Yeah, this is this is called uh I
created a monster/h how to turn [ __ ]
into gold. So u and it's we're this is
like a positive episode, so this is
perfect. So a few months ago, I I kind
of alluded to it, but I didn't want to
like say it. My sister-in-law got breast
cancer recently, and which sucks because
she's pregnant. She's due uh in October
and she got cancer like the same so the
same day Ben called me, she called me uh
she called uh my wife and she was like,
"Okay, this is horrible. I'm pregnant
and I have cancer.
How could I make this awesome?" And so
she got inspired and I guess got
inspired by me because everything that
was taking way too much credit, but uh
but it runs in the family.
pulled you over for a speeding violation
there on that sentence. But go ahead.
You citation back on the road.
>> Yeah, I'm the pregnant one with cancer,
but you are the hero, Sam. Uh,
but I guess what I'm saying like, you
know, as you know, being a creator, you
get a lot of free stuff and I think
everyone's like, I want that. I want I
want a free mattress. And so she started
making Tik Toks about being pregnant and
having cancer. And she's like doing
amazing where like the video I don't
like watching is like when she finally
shaves her head, it always makes me cry.
But then there's like her working out
and doing stuff and like she's like
basically starts off every video. I'm 30
years old. I'm pregnant and I have
cancer and like here's my workout today.
And she now is on TikTok. She's getting
like tens of thousands of views on a
bunch of videos. I think she's doing
like a video a day. But I just thought
this was really awesome. I thought this
was really really really cool and
admirable what she's doing because
getting cancer and being pregnant that's
literally like one of the worst lots
that can be drawn ever. Uh but she and
and I like to tease her because I'm like
the shitty thing about both of those
things your shtick is that ideally
they're going to end. You're going to
have a baby and the cancer is going to
go away. So you better get everything
out of this you know while you can. But
I think it's pretty cool and I thought
you'd get a kick out of this uh what
she's doing.
>> I do I I am getting a kick out of I
think this is awesome. I'm going to
watch some of these videos after this.
Um, I do have a suggestion now that
she's taking suggestions.
I do have a suggestion.
>> Well, she's in the arena now.
>> Well, kind of like you said, like, you
know, the the uh that initial hook is
like obviously like a p a shock, right?
Like I'm 30 years old, I'm pregnant, and
I have cancer.
>> By the way, let me let me give her a
shout out. It's uh Sid Glander. Her
first name is Sydney.
>> Yeah. Her first name is Sydney, last
name Glander. G L A N D E R. Okay, go
ahead.
>> Yeah, everyone, let's go follow her. Um,
I think she should tweak a little bit.
Maybe try
>> I'm 30 years old. I'm, you know, I'm a
expecting mom and future cancer
survivor. Cuz I think the words
>> matter, the label you put on yourself,
the identity, especially as a content
creator, you there's this weird thing
where the more public you are about an
identity, the harder it is to ever
switch it. And this is one she would
want to switch. not having it, but
surviving it, you know, like conquering
it, you beating it. And so that's my
that's my my only suggestion is uh is
consider consider that.
>> Yeah, I actually think that's great
advice. She's been texting me. She's
like, Kettle and Fire reached out to me.
They're offering to send me free bone
broth. And it's like, I made it. Like
every influencer has this moment. It's
sort of like making your first dollar.
The first time a brand reaches out to
you and offers like product, you're
like, I did it. And so I think it's
really cool that she's she's done. I got
um I got a huge box of Chomps from Pete
from Chomps at my door and like all the
kids on my uh my son's soccer team just
thought like they don't know what a
podcast is. They actively don't want to
watch this. But the fact that Chomps
sends me free Chomps, they were like,
"This is unbelievable." Cuz I don't know
if you know this, but kids kids freaking
love Chomps. Chopsticks.
>> Dude, Pete from Chomps, DM me. I want
some Chomps. That's like one of the few
things I would gladly accept. It's like
a lifetime supply of chomps that I have
at the front door right now.
>> Is it really?
>> Can I tell you a can I tell you a fun uh
a funny uh just like this is the uh the
tales from the house episode? So, I
don't I don't know about you.
>> Is this sponsored by
>> this is No, I need like a like a like a
insurance home insurance company maybe
like
>> Geico or something like that for this
one. So, it was unrelated to the to to
business or anything like that, but I
don't know if you if you're if you guys
are like this, but does uh does Sarah
like panic when guests are coming over?
>> She seems cool as a cucumber. If
anybody's ever cool as a cucumber,
literally cool as a cucumber. Maybe
you're the one who would be who'd be
panicking. But my wife,
>> she's pretty pretty stoic, but I do I do
empathize with that. Like when you clean
before the cleaning lady comes.
>> Yeah. So, this is like the extreme
version of that where my wife like we
have the Tesla Model X, which is
awesome, but the she hates the doors.
And I was like, "Oh, well, look, it's so
convenient to get it out." She's like,
"No, everyone can see in our car at
school drop off. Like, I open up the
kimono every time. Everyone sees every
goldfish that's on the ground." I'm
like, "They don't see your care." She's
like, "No, like park over there farther
away so nobody will see when we open our
trunk." So, anyways, we're cleaning out
the house. We're getting rid of some
toys. And so, my she doesn't want to get
she doesn't want to waste it. So, she
posts on her IG like, "Hey, does anyone
want to take these toys? Like, pick up
these toys." Um, and um her friend who's
a kindergarten teacher is like, "Oh,
perfect. I'll take them for the
classroom. And she's like, "Oh, great.
Okay, great. I'm so glad these are going
to a good place." Awesome. She puts it
like as like up front, like right by the
door. Just come grab them and go. And so
5 minutes before she picked it up, she
pick it up. She's like, "Hey, we're on
our way." And then my wife's like,
"Who's we? Oh no, who's coming?" And
she's like, "Yeah, it's me, husband, all
the kids. We're just going to come over
for real quick. We're just going to do
this." And so we're in emergency clean
mode. She's cleaning downstairs. She
starts going upstairs and I'm like like
nobody's going to go upstairs. Like
don't worry. Like this is like comical.
Nobody's going to go nobody's going to
see that room. Don't even worry about
it. Yeah, if you want to pick up some
stuff here that's fine, but like don't
worry.
>> Have you ever seen those videos where
like uh people get pulled over by the
police and they want to prove a point
and they barely roll their window down
>> and they just like I don't answer
questions. That's like basically
>> that's what she was trying to do. Yeah,
>> she wanted to like crack the thing open
and like do like an exchange through the
like slot like a prisoner in like a like
solitary confinement.
>> Um anyways, they come over, kids are
playing around the house. It's time to
go and um and they're like, "Oh." And
they're cuz they're like calling his
name, the kid their kid's name, and
they're like, "Ah, he's doing that thing
again." And we're like, "What?" And they
they're like, "He always does this. We
go to someone's house and he just goes
and finds a random room in their house
that just hides there." And we're like,
"Oh, that's funny. He's so silly. And
they're like, "No, it's not funny cuz he
won't come out. Like he'll go an hour,
two hours, like you you won't find him."
>> And then we're like, "Oh." And then my
wife starts to She's like, "Let me go
upstairs and just see real quick." And
they're like, "No, no, no. You don't
know this kid. I know how he thinks. We
will go send a search party up and find
him." So they go upstairs. Dude, your
wife's like, "Belly." And by the way,
>> exactly. By the way, the husband is a
real estate agent, so he's like, you
know, just finally attuned. just paying
attention to home.
>> Scoping the sitch.
>> He scopes the joint out. And so he he's
going room to room.
>> And my wife's just following him, making
excuses in each room like we we haven't
had a chance yet to clean that up. We're
actually we're moving. That's why this
is like this. And like I don't know who
did that. Somebody came here did that.
And so she's just making excuses while
he's opening up every closet, every
drawer, looking under the beds, like
everywhere you would never think anyone
would go. Linen closet. What's in there?
And so cuz he might be anywhere. And
finally in the last room finds him
inside of a closet and um like they're
coming down the stairs and like you know
I feel like my wife just saw a dead body
and like I think it might be hers that
she saw on the way out and she we didn't
talk for like 15 minutes after they
left. It was just like stylist and she
just processed like her worst nightmare
like playing out.
>> But you know like the med the the stoic
thing where you like visualize your
worst fear.
>> Yeah. She lived it and I feel like she
came out a better person now that like
she survived her her worst nightmare.
So, I thought I'd share that with you.
>> Does she know that you're going to talk
about it?
>> No, no, no. So, she gets to relive it
now. Thankfully, she's never listened to
an episode of the podcast. So, we're
safe. This is a safe space here.
>> We used to have this uh email that would
get sent to on the hustle. It was we
called it the zombie email. So, emails
who have never opened the email ever
before uh to like re-engage them. And it
was like, "Hey, I'm sending you this
email because according to our records,
you've never opened an email." which
gives me an opportunity right now to
explain some of my deepest darkest
secrets because no one's reading this.
So when I was 12, I open mouth kissed a
cousin once. Uh not only not only can I
not see why George Clooney is attractive
to women, I too think he's incredibly
attractive and I would uh like we would
like say all these like crazy stuff and
it was like a huge hit. Like the few
people that would actually open it, we
would totally get them back on the hook.
>> Just when they thought they were out,
you want them back, dude. That's your
That's so funny.
>> This is your zombie newsletter.
>> This was a pod full of laughs, full of
goodness. Congratulations. We did it.
And that's it. That's the pod.